

Brian Ray

Profile

I'm a Software Developer who is passionate about learning and fascinated with teaching robots to solve everyday human problems.

Skills

Ruby on Rails Object-Oriented Programming Ruby
JavaScript BDD GIT
Angular HTML CSS

Projects

ignitebot.com, Code Fellows collaboration 2015

Collaborated with 2 individuals to build a fully functioning authenticated, authorized, designed and deployed web app in 1 week. Ignitebot talks to your social network promoting ideas, garnering support for any cause i.e.: a business, a deal, an event, or a party. Personally implemented O-auth, devise and the schema configuration. My initial idea, scrum leader highlighting the power of RoR. #RoR #HTML #CSS

CaseHawk.com, Code Fellows collaboration 2015

Experienced dealing with an extensive production app, from which I personally created an Angular Front end for a REPORTS tab, that lists attributes of each case in a CSV format. Worked within a 5 person team to debug and present new features on a deadline. #Angular #RoR #JS #HTML #CSS

Work Experience

Assistant Sales Manager, Ethos Consulting Group, Denver, CO-2012-2014

- Consistently in the top 10% of sales out of over 500 representatives, top 5% for over 1 year
- Personally Sold over 700 sales totaling \$870,000+ revenue in a 2 year period.
- Interviewed and recruited over 100 candidates to sell telecom in Face to Face sales (B2C)
- Built, trained and grew a sales team of 12 people producing \$50,000+ per week
- Developed and drove an office of 40 people to become the #1 (of 354) in gross revenue

Project Manager, Comnet Wireless Inc – 2006-2009

- Developed an Excel worksheet saving \$2000+ in shipping costs, and 12-18 man-hours/wk
- Figurehead for 5-10 projects at any given time, managed 10 professionals
- Built over twenty large-scale commercial cellular phone towers

Project Manager, VMR Group - 2004-2006

- Responsible for scheduling, coordinating, purchasing and completion of residential homes
- Attained a General Contractor's license managing contractors twice my age
- Provided a 30% average ROI for investors

Education

Code Fellows – Seattle, WA - 2015 Certificate, Ruby on Rails Development

University of Colorado - Boulder, CO 2004

Bachelors of Science, Finance